（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）カイト…　レイツェル。
Kaito...
Raetsel...
She's Raetsel?
（フリーセル）彼女が　レイツェル…。
一体　何を!?
What's going on?
Rook! Freecell!
（大門カイト）ルーク！　フリーセル！
Quite a combination there.
（逆之上ギャモン）随分　珍しい
組み合わせじゃねえか。
Yeah...
（井藤ノノハ）
そうだね…って　のんきな事
言ってる場合じゃないでしょ。
Wait, that's not the problem here!
（ルーク）カイト
君たちは　今　どこにいるんだ？
Kaito, where are you guys now?
（モニター）「マヤの　ピラミッドの中だ」。
Inside a Mayan pyramid.
（モニター・ルーク）
「僕たちは　パズルを解くために→
We're in a pyramid in Egypt to solve a puzzle too.
エジプトのピラミッドに来ているんだ」。
お前らも　ピラミッドに？
You're in a pyramid too?
（アナ・グラム）
２つのピラミッド…　２つのパズル。
Two pyramids. Two puzzles.
You noticed?
（モニター・レイツェル）「気付いた？
そう。　全部　私が仕組んだ事よ」。
You're right. It's all my doing.
（モニター・レイツェル）「マヤのピラミッドと
エジプトのピラミッド…。→
A Mayan pyramid and an Egyptian pyramid.
この２つのパズルは
連動しているのよ。→
These two puzzles are connected.
ルーク…　君たちが　エジプトのピラミッドを
調べるって聞いた時に→
Rook, you inspired me when you said you wanted to check out Egyptian pyramids.
ひらめいちゃったの。→
大門カイトを　ここ　マヤのピラミッドに
おびき寄せ→
I'd lure Daimon Kaito here, then lock you all up in these two pyramids.
君たち全員を
２つのピラミッドに閉じ込める」。
永遠にね。
Forever and ever.
で　作り替えたの。
So I rebuilt them.
These ruins were totally empty with no treasures whatsoever.
財のない　空っぽだった
２つの遺跡を→
大門カイトを財とする
飛びっきり難しいパズルにね。
Now, this is an insanely difficult puzzle with Daimon Kaito as the treasure!
空っぽ？
They were empty?
くっ…。　ジンの偽もんまで使って
手の込んだ事しやがって！
You even sent us a fake Jin! You sure crossed a line here!
（エニグマ）ファイ・ブレインの子供たちを
一網打尽にするパズルか…。
This puzzle can put an end to all the children of the Phi Brain at once.
すばらしい。→
Wonderful.
Raetsel, I was right to make a contract with you.
レイツェル　やはり　君との契約は
間違いじゃなかった。→
Rook and Freecell are both fundamentally Givers.
ルークと　フリーセル
２人の本来の資質は　ギヴァーだ。→
ソルヴァーとして　レイツェルのパズルに
どこまで抵抗できるかな？
I wonder how long will they last against Raetsel's puzzle.
（ルーク）
このピラミッドが空っぽだって？→
This pyramid? Empty?
レイツェル…
君は　何も分かっていない。
Raetsel, you understand nothing.
僕たちの事も　このパズルの事も。
Neither about us, nor this whole puzzle.
僕たちは　このパズルを解き
カイトたちを救い出し→
We'll solve this puzzle, save Kaito and the others, and get the hidden treasure.
隠された財を　手に入れる。
見せてあげよう
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちの実力を！
Let's show you the true potential of the children of the Phi Brain!
ルーク…。
（口笛）
言うねえ。
Rook...
Big words.
準備はいいか？　フリーセル君。
いつでも！　ルーク君。
Are you ready, Freecell?
Any time, Rook.
隠された財？
何　言ってるんだか…。
Hidden treasure? Are you high?
ルールを説明するわ。
Let me explain the rules.
（タブレット・レイツェル）
「これは　２人が同時に行う
遺跡を使った迷路よ。→
This is a maze among the ruins that must be solved by two people simultaneously.
壁に　神様のエンブレムが
刻まれてるでしょ？」。
You see the paintings of the gods on the walls?
あっ　これか…。
This?
Amun. Atum. Geb. Horus. Osiris. Ra. Shu.
（タブレット・レイツェル）「アメン　アトゥム　ゲブ
ホルス　オシリス　ラー　シュー。→
エンブレムに触れると
別のエンブレムの付いた壁が→
If you touch an emblem, it will move along with the walls of another emblem. You can progress like that.
連動して動き
先に進めるようになるわ」。
You proceed by opening the path for each other.
（タブレット・レイツェル）
「交互に壁を開いて　進み→
迷路中央に到達できれば
君たちの勝ちよ」。
You win if you can reach the center of the maze.
なるほど…。　だから
別々の入り口から始めるんだ。
I see. So that's why we had to start from different entrances.
You have ten minutes.
（タブレット・レイツェル）
「制限時間は　１０分。→
If you don't make it, all the doors will be locked and you'll never get out.
それを過ぎれば　全ての扉が閉じ
外には出られなくなるからね。→
永遠に…。→
Never.
私が本気で作った　パズル→
I'm serious about this puzzle.
Challenge it with that in mind.
覚悟して挑む事ね」。
フリーセル君
まずは　エンブレムのある壁を探そう。
Freecell, we should look for walls with emblems first.
（フリーセル）そうだね。　エンブレムの配置と
法則性を突き止めるんだ。
That's right. We need to figure out the positions and the system behind the emblems.
ホルス。
Horus!
Shu is the key to open Geb!
ゲブを開く鍵は…　シューだ！
I see!
（ルーク）そうか。
（フリーセル）オシリス　触れるよ。
Let's try Osiris.
Horus opened.
ホルスが開いた。　エンブレムは→
The emblems are connected in the order of
アトゥム　シュー　ゲブ　オシリス　ホルス　アメン　ラーの
順番でつながっている！
Atum, Shu, Geb, Osiris, Horus, Amun, and Ra.
So if we can't move on, we just have to find the emblem to open the wall in our way.
（ヘッドセット・フリーセル）「進めなくなったら
その壁を開くためのエンブレムを→
探せばいいんだね」。
We don't have much time. Let's use the shortest route.
（ルーク）時間は限られている。
（モニター・ルーク）「最短ルートで行こう！」。
（モニター・フリーセル）「分かった」。
Okay!
やるじゃない。　こんなに早く
関係性を見抜くなんて。
Not bad.
They figured out the relationships quite quick.
Atum next!
（ルーク）次は　アトゥム。
（ルーク）こちらだと
先で　迷路がつながる…。→
This way our paths can connect. This is it!
ならば　こっちだ！
心の声
（ルーク）必ず解放する。→
I'm gonna solve this,
save Kaito, get the treasure,
カイトを救い　財を手に入れ
ジンの記憶を…！
and return Jin's memories too!
Rook, you're fabulous! So fast!
心の声
（フリーセル）さすが　ルーク君…　速い！
まだか　フリーセル君。
Are you there yet, Freecell?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…　うっ…。
心の声
（フリーセル）これ以上
ルーク君が　スピードを上げたら→
If Rook speeds up any further, I won't be able to keep up with him.
ついていけなくなる…。
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…　ハッ。
Amun's next!
次は　アメンだ！→
ここに　アメン。
Amun's here.
（フリーセル）ここにも　アメン！→
Amun's here too.
こっちのアメンか!?
Is it this Amun?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
この　オシリスの配置は…。
This Osiris...
（ヘッドセット・ルーク）
「どうした？　フリーセル君」。
What's wrong, Freecell?
いや…　何でもない。
Nothing.
次は　シューだ。
Shu's next.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
（ヘッドセット・ルーク）「フリーセル君！」。
Freecell!
There's no Shu anywhere around here!
そ…　それが…
シューが　どこにもないんだ！
どういう事だ…
なぜ　次に進めない？
What's going on? Why can't we move on?
（タブレット・レイツェル）
「いくら考えても無駄よ」。
Don't even bother trying to figure it out.
「解けるはずないもの」。
There's no way you could solve this.
まさか　答えがないのか!?
Are you telling me there's no solution?
「言ったでしょ。→
I told you that the point is to lock you up for eternity.
これは　君たちを永遠に
閉じ込めるためのパズルだって」。
This will be fine, right, Jin?
これでいいのよね…　ジン。
くっ…　どうすればいい!?
What should we do?
心の声
（ルーク）どうすれば…
どうすれば　このパズルを…。
How? How can we solve this puzzle?
（ヘッドセット・フリーセル）「ここまでかもね」。
I've had enough.
What, Freecell?
（ヘッドセット・ルーク）「フリーセル君!?　何を…」。
I've had enough of challenging this puzzle as a Solver.
（フリーセル）ソルヴァーとして
このパズルに挑むのはね。
でも…　ギヴァーとしての僕たちなら→
But as Givers we might still stand a chance.
まだ　何かできるかもしれない。
（ヘッドセット・ルーク）「えっ？」。
（フリーセル）永遠に出られない　誰かを
閉じ込めるためのパズルなら…。
I've made puzzles to lock someone up for eternity myself.
（ヘッドセット・フリーセル）
「僕も　作った事があるから」。
（ルーク）あのころの僕たちなら→
Back then we could understand and see through this puzzle.
このパズルを理解し
読み解く事ができる…。→
すごいな　フリーセル君。
（ヘッドセット・フリーセル）「えっ？」。
You're quite something, Freecell.
やってみよう！　思い出すんだ
あの時の自分を…。
Let's try and remember who we were back then!
（キュービック・Ｇ）来た道を戻っていく!?
They're going back?
They've got no time!
（ギャモン）もう　時間がねえぞ！
何をするつもり？
What are they trying to do?
心の声
（ルーク）パズルに相手を
閉じ込めるなら…　どうする？
How would I lock someone up forever?
心の声
（フリーセル）永遠に出られないように
するには　どうすれば…。
How would I design it so that they could never escape?
心の声
（ルーク）理解できるはずだ。→
I should be able to understand it.
僕は　パズルに思いを込め
カイトの永遠になろうとした。
I put all my might into puzzles to become an eternity for Kaito.
心の声
（フリーセル）僕は　パズルに思いを込め→
I put all my might into puzzles to make my time with Kaito last forever.
カイトとの時間を
永遠にしようとした。→
必ず理解できる。　僕たちなら…。
I know I can understand it.
I know we can.
あっ!?　ここは…。
This spot... I felt it earlier too.
心の声
（フリーセル）さっきも感じた…→
近くに２か所ある
アメンの壁の違和感。
These walls of Amun nearby feel off.
僕なら　もう一方のアメンの先を
袋小路にして→
I'd make the other Amun lead to a dead end and catch Kaito.
カイトを捕まえる。
うん。　僕も　カイトを逃さないために
そうするね。
I'd do the same to keep him from escaping.
心の声
（フリーセル）ここで　道を誤ったんだ。
We can't lose our way here.
Once more...
心の声
（ルーク）ここから　もう一度…。
（ルーク　フリーセル）パズルタイムの始まりだ！
It's puzzle time!
ルーク。
フリーセル君。
Rook...
Freecell...
Our perfect, unsolvable puzzles, fell in front of Kaito.
心の声
（ルーク）僕たちが
本気で作り　完璧に組み上げた→
答えのないパズルも
カイトには解かれてしまった。
心の声
（フリーセル）きっと　あるはずだ…。
このパズルにも→
Raetsel too must've made some mistake with this puzzle.
レイツェルの　ほころびが！
心の声
（フリーセル）アトゥムがない!?
行き止まりか？
There's no Atum!
Is this a dead end?
（フリーセル）
でも　今までになかった配置だ。
もしかして　これが…。
But I haven't seen this here before.
Maybe this is...
レイツェルの　ほころび…。
Raetsel's mistake?
み～つけた。
Found you.
準備は　いいかい？
ルーク君。
Are you ready, Rook?
Anytime, Freecell.
（ヘッドセット・ルーク）
「いつでも。　フリーセル君」。
いくよ！
Let's do it!
今だ！
Now!
まさか…　２つの壁が
同時に開いている一瞬を使って!?
They used the brief moment both walls are open?
行け！
Go!
解けた。
We solved it.
やったな！　ルーク　フリーセル！
You did it, Rook, Freecell!
そんな解き方があったなんて…。
（モニター・ルーク）「すごいパズルだったよ」。
It could be solved like that?
It was an amazing puzzle.
強く　厳しく
そして　正しいパズルだった。
It was strong, harsh, and just right.
まるで　カイトみたいにね。
Reminded me of Kaito.
（モニター・ルーク）「僕たちを
永遠に閉じ込めるための」…。
Even this puzzle, designed to lock us in forever, had a solution.
このパズルにも　答えはあった。
無意識かもしれないが　君は→
It might've been unintentional, but you made it solvable.
ちゃんと
解けるパズルにしてくれていたんだ。
That's why we could comprehend the puzzle as Givers, and managed to solve it.
だから　僕たちは　ギヴァーとして
このパズルを理解し　解く事ができた。
何なのよ　それ…。
What does that even mean?
（スピーカー・エニグマ）
「君の負け　という事だ」。
It means that you lose.
ここは　下がりたまえ。
Step down.
もはや　小娘一人で
どうにかなる状況ではない。
This isn't a situation some little girl can handle by herself.
うっ…。　でも　私は諦めない！
I'm not gonna give up!
待て　レイツェル！　ジンは　どこだ!?
Wait, Raetsel! Where's Jin?
恐れていたとおりになったか…。→
It went just as I feared it would.
覚悟を口にしてはいたが
レイツェルの無意識の優しさ…。
Raetsel claimed she had the determination, but deep within she was still soft.
それが　あだになるとは…。→
To think that would be her downfall.
Damn children of the Phi Brain.
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちめ。
What?!
な…　何？
（ギャモン）やべえ　崩れる！
Crap! It's collapsing!
あった！
Wait!
ルーク君　それは？
What's that, Rook?
隠された財は　２つのスイッチを
同時に押す事で現れるらしい。
The hidden treasure is said to be revealed by pushing two switches at once.
だが　ここには１つしか…。
But there's only one switch here.
待って　ルーク君。　２つのスイッチ？
Wait, Rook. There are two switches.
２つのピラミッド…。
And two pyramids.
２つのパズル！
カイト！
And two puzzles.
Kaito, is there some kind of a switch in that room?
（モニター・ルーク）
「その部屋に　スイッチのようなものが
ないか調べてくれ」。
Look around!
スイッチ!?
A switch?
アナが思うに　これ？
I think... this?
あったぞ　ルーク！
Found it, Rook!
（モニター・ルーク）「５つ数える。
同時に押してくれ！」。
I'll count down from five.
Let's push them at the same time!
分かった！
（モニター・ルーク）「いくぞ。　５　４」。
Gotcha.
Let's do this.
5. 4. 3. 2. 1.
３　２　１　ゼロ！
Zero!
That?
（フリーセル）これは…。
（ルーク）ピタゴラス文書だ！
The Pythagoras Scriptures!
（ルーク）これに　賢者ピタゴラスが残した→
The secrets of the Divine Puzzle are inscribed in them by the philosopher Pythagoras.
神のパズルに関する秘密が
記されている。
この財を封じるために→
So the two puzzles were connected to hide this treasure?
２つのパズルは
連動していたってのか。
We've gotta get out of here!
脱出しよう！
Thanks, Rook, Freecell!
ありがとよ！　ルーク　フリーセル！
こいつは　ＰＯＧ本部に　必ず届ける。
（モニター・ルーク　フリーセル）「ああ！」。
I'll take this to the POG HQ!
Okay!
急げ！
ノノハ　ファイトー！
Hurry!
Nonoha, fight!
私…　また　この役目!?
Is that my role again?
（ルーク　フリーセル）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
We made it.
何とか　助かったね。
ありがとう　フリーセル君。
Thanks, Freecell.
おかげで　ピタゴラス文書を
手に入れる事ができた。
Thanks to you, we found the Pythagoras Scriptures.
ううん　ルーク君のおかげさ。
That honor is yours, Rook.
Don't be so formal.
（ルーク）ルーク…。
いいよ　「ルーク」で。
We're friends.
え…　じゃあ
僕の事も　「フリーセル」で。
Then let's put aside all formalities from now on.
Hey!
（ピノクル）お～い！
フリーセル！
Freecell!
（ビショップ）ルーク様！
Sir Rook!
（軸川ソウジ）
見事　ピタゴラス文書を手に入れた
ようですね　ルーク管理官は。
Quite impressive. Chief Rook got the Pythagoras Scriptures.
That goes for you too.
（解道バロン）ご苦労さまでした。→
Nice job securing all these state secrets.
まさか　ここまでの重要機密を
手に入れてくれるとは。
いえいえ。　おいしかったですよ
アムギーネ共和国の　アップルパイ。
Please.
The Amginean apple pies were just amazing.
ヨハン・ジーグムント・エニグマ大統領…。→
President Johan Sigmund Enigma.
世界中のパズラーを
滅ぼそうとしている者が→
He works to rid the Earth of all puzzlers.
なぜ　真方ジンの過去
そして　神のパズルについても→
Why would such a man know so much about Makata Jin's past and the Divine Puzzle?
深く知っていたのか…。
そして　賢者ピタゴラスのパズル。
Not to mention philosopher Pythagoras' puzzle.
ルーク管理官すら知らなかった
大がかりな仕掛けを→
Not even Chief Rook knew about that huge trap.
How did he know then?
なぜ　彼が知っていたのか。
彼が　かつて　あのパズルの
管理者だったとすれば→
What if he was the overseer of that puzzle once?
説明がつきます。→
That would explain it.
これで　全てが　つながりました。
Now it all makes sense.
心の声
（バロン）お前だったのか…。
So it was you?
ジン…。
Jin...
Hi, Jin!
ジン　ただいま。
What's wrong, Jin?
（レイツェル）どうしたの!?　ジン。
There's no can opener.
（真方ジン）缶切りが　ないんだ。
缶切りを使わず
どうやって開けるか…。
How does one open a can without a can opener?
これは…　難しいパズル…　だ…。
This is a difficult puzzle.
あぁ～！　ジン!?
ちょっと…　しっかりして！
Jin! Wake up!
Phew, that was close.
（ジン）
いや～　危ないところだったよ。
Geez, are you stupid?
もう　バカ！　缶切りくらい
買いに行けばよかったでしょ。
Why didn't you just go and buy a can opener?
（ジン）
この町の事は　何も知らないし→
I don't know anything about this town,
and you told me not to go anywhere. That I should just mind the house.
「どこにも行かないで　留守番を
お願い」と　君に言われたからね。
だから　ずっと待っててくれたの？
So you waited all this time?
ありがとう　ジン。
Thanks, Jin.
Eat up!
いっぱい食べてね！
心の声
（レイツェル）私の本気のパズルが
解かれた…。
I was serious about that puzzle, and yet they solved it.
心の声
（レイツェル）このままでは　いつか…。→
I don't know how long can I keep—
It's okay! I haven't lost yet!
大丈夫！　私は　まだ負けてない。→
しばらく　この町で身を隠して…。
I'll just hide in this town for a while, then...
（ジン）それで　いいのか？
Are you fine with that?
え？
考えていた。
I gave it some thought.
お前と　カイト　真に必要な者は
どちらなのか…。
Who do I really need: you or Kaito?
何を言っているの…　ジン？
What are you saying, Jin?
[無線]
Enigma?!
エニグマ。
[無線]
何？　こんな時間に。
What do you want this late?
[無線]（エニグマ）緊急事態だ　レイツェル。→
This is an emergency, Raetsel!
The POG's found your hideout!
ＰＯＧが　君たちの　その隠れ家を
突き止めたようだ。→
間もなく　彼らが来る。
They'll be there soon.
If you don't want them to take Jin, then hurry!
[無線]最愛のジンを
奪われたくなければ→
今すぐに…。
（レイツェル）あ…。
フッ…
さて　ＰＯＧにも教えてやるか。→
Now then.
I guess I should tell the POG where they are.
彼らの居場所を…。
Raetsel, you're not allowed to catch your breath.
（エニグマ）
レイツェル…　君に休息の時はない。
追い込まれて　追い込まれて
追い込まれてこそ→
You're cornered.
Cats only unleash their full wrath when they are truly cornered.
猫は　凶暴に
どう猛にもなるんだ。→
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちを倒すには
もっと強く…。→
You need more than that to beat the children of the Phi Brain.
Right, Lovushka?
だろ？　ラブーシュカ。
心の声
（レイツェル）やるしかない…。→
I must do it.
大門カイトと
命を懸けて戦うしか…！
I must fight Daimon Kaito to the death.
Preview
It was you, wasn't it, Jikukawa?
No, I didn't do a thing!